

### **Profile**

I am a PhD student specializing in sparse optimization and its application in image processing. Trilingual and with a multinational background, I am a fast learner striving to develop my knowledge in applied mathematics and computer science.

## Experience

PhD-MORPHEME team at INRIA/I<sub>3</sub>S/iBV 10/2017-

Sophia Antipolis

### PhD title: Reconstruction for 3D TIRF-MA fluorescence microscopy imaging Signal / image processing & Sparse optimization

- Working on different methods to minimize the constrained l2-lo minimization problem.
- Reconstruction of Single-Molecule localization microscopy images.

Internship-MORPHEME team at INRIA/I3S/iBV 03/2017-08/2017

Sophia Antipolis

Sparse optimization

Working on a relaxation of the constrained l2-lo minimization problem.

#### Internship-Technical university of Denmark 06/2016-08/2016

Copenhagen

Colour image processing

Searching a new variational model that exploits correlation between channels in multispectral images. Testing the proposed model with the minimization algorithms PALM and ADMM.

### Internship-Norwegian Defence Research establishment 06/2015-08/2015

Oslo

- Scanned projectile fragments using both a normal camera and a 3D scanner.
- Wrote a program that analyzed the geometric of the fragments to find the shape factor.

### Internship-Norwegian Defence Research establishment 06/2014-08/2014

Oslo

High-speed video analysing

Developed a program that analyzed video of test firings with a newly developed ammunition, finding the speed of each fragment as well as impact coordinate

### Internship-Norwegian Defence Research establishment 06/2013-08/2013

Oslo

Radar frequency analysing

Developed a program that analyzed radar frequencies used under difficult conditions

## **Publications**

Arne Bechensteen and Laure Blanc-Féraud and Gilles Aubert. New l2-lo algorithm for single-molecule localization microscopy. Biomedical Optics Express 11(2) 2020

Arne Bechensteen and Laure Blanc-Féraud and Gilles Aubert. Exact biconvex reformulation fo the l2-lo minimization problem GRETSI 2019

Arne Bechensteen and Laure Blanc-Féraud and Gilles Aubert. New Methods for 12lo Minimization and their Applications to 2D Single-Molecule Localization Microscopy. 2019 IEEE 16th International Symposium on Biomedical Imaging

## Internal publication

Tallak H. Risdal, Arne H. Bechensteen. High-speed video of APEX test firings: Results of data reduction to determine fragment velocities and direction. Norwegian Defence Research establishment (FFI) report no: 14/01621. Confidential publication.

### **Details**

01/10/1991 12 Avenue Saint Jean Baptiste o6ooo Nice France +33667892799 arnebechen@gmail.com Webpage: https://abechens.github.io/

### Education

INSA Toulouse 2012-2017

Mathematical and modeling engineering

Exchange Student-Universität Hamburg 2016-2017 (1 semester)

Modelling and simulations of complex systems

# **Teaching**

Image processing (Traitement Numérique des Images) 5th year Polytech Nice Sophia

**Applied AI** 5<sup>th</sup> year Polytech Nice Sophia

**Advanced Machine** Learning 5th year Polytech Nice Sophia

# Languages

Norwegian

English

French

### **Tools**

**MATLAB** 

Python